这是二零二四年大庆市初中升学考试英语听力测试部分。
测试共分为两节。
听力考试正式开始。
听下面五段对话。
啊，每段对话后有一个小题，
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
每段对话仅读一遍。
每段对话之间，你将有五秒钟的作答和阅读下一小题的时间
How is the weather?
It is raining outside.
Take an umbrella with you.
What can I do for you?
I'd like to buy a t -shirt.
Oh, Jack, did you watch the baseball match on TV last night?
Of course, that's my favorite sport.
Mike, how do you usually go to work?
I usually drive to work.
Hurry up, Mary.
The film is going to start.
Don't worry. It starts at 3 o
There is still much time left.
Part 2. Choose the right answer according to the dialogue or passage you hear.
听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从。题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你都有五秒钟时间阅读各个小题。
听完每段对话后，将给出十秒钟的作答时间。
每。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听第六段材料，回答第六至七题
Good morning. May I take your order?
Yes, I'd like a cup of iced tea.
Would you like something to eat?
I'd like a hamburger.
Anything else? No, thanks.
Good morning. May I take your order?
Yes, I'd like a cup of iced tea.
Would you like something to eat?
I'd like a hamburger.
Anything else? No, thanks.
听第七段材料，回答。
第八至九题。
Can I help you?
Well, I've got a headache.
How long have you been like this?
For about two days.
Let me take your temperature.
You have a fever.
Then what should I do?
You should take the medicine three times a day and drink more water.
Can I help you?
Well, I've got a headache.
How long have you been like this?
For about two days.
Let me take your temperature.
You have a fever.
Then what should I do?
You should take the medicine three times a day and drink more water.
听第八段材料，回答第十至十二题
Hey, what are you doing?
I'm getting ready for the test.
Do you mean the English test next Friday?
Yes, but I'm so worried.
I'm not good at English at all.
I think English is easy for me, but math is a big problem.
Oh, I do well in math.
We can help each other.
That's a good idea.
We can study together in the library tomorrow.
Okay, let's meet there at eight o in the morning.
Hey, what are you doing?
I'm getting ready for the test.
Do you mean the English test next Friday?
Yes, but I'm so worried.
I'm not good at English at all.
think English is easy for me, but math is a big problem.
Oh, I do well in math.
We can help each other.
That's a good idea.
We can study together in the library tomorrow.
Okay, let's meet there at eight o in the
听第九段材料，回答第十三至十五题
Hi, Tony, you are reading The Adventures of Tom Sawyer.
Yeah, I've read it four times.
Every time I read it, I learn something new.
Who is it written by?
It is by Mark Twain.
What is it about?
It is a lovely story full of fun.
In the story, Tom and his friend Hawk have many adventures.
That sounds interesting.
I'd like to buy one.
Where did you get it?
Right Star Bookshop.
Is it far from here?
No, it's a 10 -minute walk.
Go along the street and turn left at the first turning.
It is on your right.
Oh, great. I'm going to get one.
Hi, Tony, you are reading The Adventures of Tom Sawyer.
Yeah, I've read it four times.
Every time I read it, I learn something new.
Who is it written by?
It is by Mark Twain.
What is it about?
It is a lovely story full of fun.
In the story, Tom and his friend Hawk have many adventures.
That sounds interesting.
I'd like to buy one.
Where did you get it?
Right Star Bookshop.
Is it far from here?
No, it's a 10 -minute walk.
Go along the street and turn left at the first turning.
It is on your right.
Oh, great. I'm going to get one.
Star it far from here?
听第十段材料，回答第十六至二十题。
It great. I'm get Star Bookshop.
Is far here?
袁隆平是
a called the father of rice because he has helped people around the world grow more
rice than before.
He was born in Beijing in 1930.
When he was 20 years old, he studied at Southwest Agriculture College.
In 1953, he finished his studies and became a teacher.
In 1964, Yuan Longping started to make a special study of rice.
Ten years later, in 1974,
he finally developed a new kind rice.
In the 1980s, he went around the world and gave farmers advice on growing rice.
In 2004, he won the World Food Prize for his work.
He has saved many people from hunger, and that is why he is a hero.
Yuan Longping is called the father of rice because he has helped people around the
world grow more rice than before.
He was born in Beijing in 1930.
When he was 20 years old, he studied at Southwest Agriculture College.
In 1953, he finished his studies and became a teacher.
In 1964, Yuan Longping started to make a special study of rice.
Ten years later, in 1974,
he finally developed a new kind rice.
In the 1980s, he went around the world and gave farmers advice on growing rice.
In 2004, he won the World Food Prize for his work.
He has saved many people from hunger, and that is why he is a